G lobalization is a complex conception and so far there is no accepted definition for it. A relatively reasonable description is that globalization is the spread of products, technology, information, and jobs across national borders and cultures(Bird,2019). This essay will analyse the positive and negative of globalization based on this defination.
About the orgin of globalization, there are some different arguments. Historian argue it began with the Silk Road two thousand years ago, which connected China and Europe. It was a trading route. Economist persist it started in 1980. They believe this is a more modern definition. A commonly acceptable opinion is that 1870 was the beginning of globalization and it was called the first wave of globalization. At that time, humans could design and product giant ship, and trains had been invented for decades of years. Therefore, it became possible to massively transport goods between different countries. Specially, the Suez Canal and the Pacific Railroad were opened in that year which were considered the symbol of the start of massive transportation. Since then, the world entered a new stage of rapid development.
PROS
It is not doubt that globalization has promoted the global economy to progress. Many countries, including developing countries, benefit from it. Because of geography, climate and other factors, the distribution of natural resources is imbalance in the world. For instance, the Middle East countries possess rich oil, but they have no farming. Japan has advanced industry, but it has a lack of natural resources. This situation calls for globalization mechanism. In fact, globalization works well. For example, China has abundant labor resources. In the past, they had to be limited in agriculture. When China joined the WTO and fitted into the global economy in 1999, this energy was released. Foreign investment was introduced and a lot of new factories were built. The emerging industries absorbed a lot of labour. In the case of Foxconn, its production needs dense labours and Chinese market is the optimum choice for it. Since it opened its first factory in China, Foxconn has maintained good growth momentum and absorbed a lot of labours. So far, it has offered over 800 thousand jobs. At the same time, China has gained a huge market space and its products have been exported to all parts of the world. Today, China has become the second largest economy in the world. Some people argue that international trade could increase the cost and leads to the rise of price. However, economist found distant transportation just has little impact on goods cost and it is less than four percent of goods cost. Furthermore, with the development of transportation technology, this cost will continue to decrease.
On the other hand, globalization has taken the active effects on cultural exchange in the world. With the development of modern communication technology, especially the emergence of the Internet, it has become easy that people from different culture learn each other. Although critics argue globalization could hurt tradional culture, we have to admit globalization makes culture much more diversified and it is beneficial to the spread and develpment of traditional culture. We probably are not aware of existence of globalization, but In fact, we are enjoying pleasant lives based on multiculture every day. For example, in Auckland, we can enjoy France steak, Italian Pizza, Hollywood moives and African music. All of these benefit from globalization. Multiculture facilitates people to understand others from different culture. It is beneficial for reducing the conflict between different countries and regions.
Globalization is a double-edge sword. Although it promote the world to progress, it also bring some negative effects to us.
CONS
Globalization has promoted the industrialization process. However, over-industrialization has caused serious damage to the environment in many countires, especially developing countries. Pollution problems have become their most important issue. India, China, Thainland and some other countries has suffered from severe pollution in the past decades. According to offcial statistics, more than 7 million people die from air pollution and water pollution each year. In the case of India, in the past ten years, it suffered serious air pollution because of industrial emission, vehicle exhaust and overuse of fossil fuels. Many cities air quality was poor. In extreme cases, flights are postponed and facotires and schools are closed. These countries’authorities have realized the problem and are taking steps to resolve the problem, but it will pay a high price. 
Gobalization’s another negative effect is that it could cause health issues for humans. Nowadays, travelling across different countires is more and more frequent. It creates conditions for the spread of diseases. History show when people come to a new environment, they could transmit diseases or become infected because the immune system of person can not defend virus from new environment. In 2014, Ebola virus outbreak in Guinea. Because of popuplation movement, the disease quickly spread to Libya, Nigeria, Spain, America and other countries within six months. This disaster killed as many as six thousands people. Globalization would make it easy for regional illnesses to become global epidemics unless controls are put in place. 

In conclusion, it is clear that Globalization has some positive aspects and negative aspects. We should analyse every aspect objectively. Globalization brings us prosperous economy and helps numerous people get rid of poverty. It also facilitates the cultural exchange between different countries and regions and brings us diversified culture. More and more countires participate in the international affairs and national borders are no longer important. On another hand, it also brings environmental pollution and health issues, which is threating human life and even survival. Resolving these issues need the cooperation of international community. Globalization is new opportunities and new challeges. We should make use of its advantages and overcome or avoid its disadvantages

